<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on notes</title>
    <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>©</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 12:13:32 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://njseeto.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 17th Nov - 24th Nov</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-24-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-24-notes/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR; Work things:  Finished a feature that adds specific information at the point of object creation, rather than enriching the object later on in the pipeline. Sprint planning → we are looking at splitting a monolithic application across two teams. Server response times in US were super slow → Caching the slow to build data solved this. Continued AWS learning → EC2, security groups and Elastic Block Storage (EBS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 3rd Nov - 16th Nov</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-17-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-17-notes/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR;  This article will cover a fortnights&amp;rsquo; worth of musings (nothing about work, all about my holiday). Australia is pretty darn great. Discovered some new fun places in Sydney → White Rabbit Gallery and Sappho Books. Channeled Thelma &amp;amp; Louise and drove the Great Ocean Road with a friend. Detoured from the Great Ocean Road and did a few hikes in the Grampians. Hikes included Mt Abrupt - Mud Dadjug, Lake Elizabeth and Griffiths Island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 27th Oct - 2nd Nov</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-03-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-03-notes/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR; Work things:  AWS Solutions Architect Certification study continues → databases are my weakness Encryption at rest: Research into encrypting data in S3 buckets and ran into the issues with preserving the &amp;lsquo;last modified date&amp;rsquo; metadata when running   aws s3 cp s3://encrypted-bucket s3://encrypted-bucket --recursive --sse  (any insight into this would be greatly appreciated).
 Completed stories to protect our application from XSS (reflected and stored).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the Intersection of Empathy and Technology</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-10-30-at-the-intersection-of-empathy-and-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 12:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-10-30-at-the-intersection-of-empathy-and-technology/</guid>
      <description>Warning: This article contains references to emotions and feelings 😊 Having an open conversation about mental health can be difficult to initiate. The invisible nature of mental health obscures our ability to determine whether someone is actually struggling. It either goes unnoticed or feels too awkward a topic to bring up.
While working as a clinician in children&amp;rsquo;s hospitals, I found myself in a number of hard discussions with families in distress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not another blog</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-10-26-not-another-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-10-26-not-another-blog/</guid>
      <description>What is this? A blog. Yes another blog.
It&amp;rsquo;s a place that I do not expect many people to deliberately seek out, stumble upon sure but not stay for long. The reason for this blog is a purely selfish one. This is a place to keep my musings and an easy way to direct people (mainly myself) to information.

What can you expect? To be perfectly honest - fairly irregular blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>