<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on notes</title>
    <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>©</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 10:13:30 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://njseeto.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithms: Binary Sort</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2020-02-22-algorithms-binary-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 10:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2020-02-22-algorithms-binary-sort/</guid>
      <description>This is part of the Algorithms series that I have decided to write up as a result of reading Grokking Algorithms book.
TL; DR  Binary search eliminates half the remaining values every time. Binary search only works if the list is sorted. Algorithm speed isn&amp;rsquo;t measured in seconds but in the growth of the number of operations. We talk about how quickly the run of the algorithm increases as the size of the input increases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS50: Week One - C</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2020-02-16-cs50/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 10:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2020-02-16-cs50/</guid>
      <description>Some notes from Week 1 of the CS50 course.  table { border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; } td, th { border: 1px solid #dddddd; text-align: left; padding: 8px; } box { width: 300px; border: 2px solid red; padding: 8px; margin: 10px; }  Data Types   Data Type Description   int Used to store integers.Since integers take up 4 bytes of memory (32 bits)   char Stores single characters; takes up 1 byte.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS50: Week One - Problem Set: Mario</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2020-02-16-cs50-pset_mario/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 10:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2020-02-16-cs50-pset_mario/</guid>
      <description>This problem set comes in two levels, more comfortable and less comfortable. I will run through both problems and my thought process for them in this post. Problem Set 1 - Mario (more comfortable) Create a pyramid in C, albeit in text, using hashes (#) for bricks, a la the below. Each hash is a bit taller than it is wide, so the pyramid itself is also be taller than it is wide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 16th Dec - 3rd Jan</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-22-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 12:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-22-note/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR; Super delayed week notes!
 Christmas in Riga Identity functions are cool Challenge assumptions Happy New Year!  Work things:  Story challenged. Assumptions here were challenged, a team wanted us to implement some metrics that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense. More on this later on. I was looking through a section of Java 8 in Action book about streams and discovered you can use methods at the point of instantiation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 9th Dec - 15th Dec</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-17-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 12:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-17-notes/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR;  Work: Cassandra, Compliance, Connecting the dots Life: Climate  Work things:  Mocks and stubs. Chatted about our Cassandra database. GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) and PECR (Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations). Found out that sometimes you need to wait 24hrs after deleting an AWS S3 bucket before it is actually deleted from the console. We had a phantom alert, ie: an alert was going off even though the metrics and graphs all looked fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tier 1 Visa</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-12-tier-1-visa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 12:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-12-tier-1-visa/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE
Criteria for this visa has recently changed. Therefore, not everything in this post may be applicable to your case. Please refer to the GovUK Tier 1 Overview page for the most up to date information.
Please refrain from asking me about your application. I am not an immigration lawyer and cannot legally advise anyone. This is not legal advice. This article comprises of general information and my personal experience with the visa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 2nd Dec - 8th Dec</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-08-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-08-notes/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR;  Work: Spies, branches and an incident. Life: Housemates, algorithms and kindness.  Work things:  Final week of compliance work (hopefully). Using Mockito Spies at work to help partially mock methods on a class. Branch based vs Trunk based development. I want to dedicate a bit more space for this discussion, but I wanted to highlight the difficulty of chasing someone down to review changes. We primarily work in a trunk-based manner (which I thoroughly enjoy) but for this particulary story I have been working on, the team decided to go with a branch based style and to have one developer working on the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 25th Nov - 1st Dec</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-01-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-12-01-notes/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR; Work things:  The Future of CyberSecurity conference → I&amp;rsquo;ll write up a quick overview of the conference when I get time. Watched Mastering Chaos - A Netflix Guide to Microservices Played around with Cloudcraft Held an event at work involving high school students and the Mayor&amp;rsquo;s Fund for London Decommissioned an application that is no longer used. It&amp;rsquo;s super satisfying deleting code. Discussed the best practice for acccessing data from a database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 17th Nov - 24th Nov</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-24-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-24-notes/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR; Work things:  Finished a feature that adds specific information at the point of object creation, rather than enriching the object later on in the pipeline. Sprint planning → we are looking at splitting a monolithic application across two teams. Server response times in US were super slow → Caching the slow to build data solved this. Continued AWS learning → EC2, security groups and Elastic Block Storage (EBS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 3rd Nov - 16th Nov</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-17-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-17-notes/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR;  This article will cover a fortnights&amp;rsquo; worth of musings (nothing about work, all about my holiday). Australia is pretty darn great. Discovered some new fun places in Sydney → White Rabbit Gallery and Sappho Books. Channeled Thelma &amp;amp; Louise and drove the Great Ocean Road with a friend. Detoured from the Great Ocean Road and did a few hikes in the Grampians. Hikes included Mt Abrupt - Mud Dadjug, Lake Elizabeth and Griffiths Island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 27th Oct - 2nd Nov</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-03-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-11-03-notes/</guid>
      <description>TL, DR; Work things:  AWS Solutions Architect Certification study continues → databases are my weakness Encryption at rest: Research into encrypting data in S3 buckets and ran into the issues with preserving the &amp;lsquo;last modified date&amp;rsquo; metadata when running   aws s3 cp s3://encrypted-bucket s3://encrypted-bucket --recursive --sse  (any insight into this would be greatly appreciated).
 Completed stories to protect our application from XSS (reflected and stored).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the Intersection of Empathy and Technology</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-10-30-at-the-intersection-of-empathy-and-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 12:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-10-30-at-the-intersection-of-empathy-and-technology/</guid>
      <description>Warning: This article contains references to emotions and feelings 😊 Having an open conversation about mental health can be difficult to initiate. The invisible nature of mental health obscures our ability to determine whether someone is actually struggling. It either goes unnoticed or feels too awkward a topic to bring up.
While working as a clinician in children&amp;rsquo;s hospitals, I found myself in a number of hard discussions with families in distress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not another blog</title>
      <link>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-10-26-not-another-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njseeto.github.io/posts/2019-10-26-not-another-blog/</guid>
      <description>What is this? A blog. Yes another blog.
It&amp;rsquo;s a place that I do not expect many people to deliberately seek out, stumble upon sure but not stay for long. The reason for this blog is a purely selfish one. This is a place to keep my musings and an easy way to direct people (mainly myself) to information.

What can you expect? To be perfectly honest - fairly irregular blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>